<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: gentoo | drwxr-xr-x mitzip]]></title>
  <link href="http://mitzip.com/categories/gentoo/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mitzip.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-23T01:45:03-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://mitzip.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[mitzip]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Home Router Hunt: Hardware]]></title>
    <link href="http://mitzip.com/home-router-hunt-hardware/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-10T14:32:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mitzip.com/home-router-hunt-hardware</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Project Goals</h3>

<ul>
<li>Build an epic wireless router/firewall. (preferring <abbr title="Open-Source Hardware">OSHW</abbr>
  and <em>requiring</em> <abbr title="Open-Source Software">OSS</abbr>)</li>
<li>It should be cheap enough to provide to family and friends.</li>
</ul>


<p>I&rsquo;ve been on the hunt for the perfect home router platform for a while.
There was a time when I thought it would be best to have my
<abbr title="Home Theater Personal Computer">HTPC</abbr>,
<abbr title="Network Attached Storage">NAS</abbr>,
<abbr title="Wireless Access Point">WAP</abbr>,
router and firewall needs all provided by the same machine. I&rsquo;ve since
concluded that putting all your eggs in one basket is often not the
best choice.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>For one, lots of work, by very intelligent and specialized individuals,
has been put into different <abbr title="Operating Systems">OSs</abbr>
and distributions that are tailored to excel at a certain task. I see no
reason to throw all that expertise away.</p>

<p>Second, the software packages needed to fulfil my needs are diverse,
but also conflicting. For example, having a <abbr title="Graphical User Interface">GUI</abbr>,
bleeding-edge HTPC software or an experimental file system running
on a router/firewall should make anyone cringe. Of course, a reboot
bringing down the whole house is rather annoying as well.</p>

<p>Finally, even if I was okay with all of those drawbacks, my second
goal puts a cap on how expensive said device can be. The hardware
required to be the end-all-be-all home computer would be
prohibitively expensive to try and provide to all my family and
friends that I support.</p>

<p><em>This post is still being written, more to come&hellip;</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
